BIPUL THAKUR

FULL STACK DEVELOPER AND ANDROID APP DEVELOPER

CONTACT

7667340560

thakurbipul353@gmail.com

https://vipul353.github.io/portfolio/

near hanuman mandir , burmu, Ranchi, Jharkhand , Pin no.-834214

SKILLS

Fullstack developer , Android App Developer

Html , css, javasript, React js,java , Spring boot, flutter

Responsive Web Development, Reuable react js Component,redux Toolkit,Spring Boot Microservices, ES5/ES6

Responsive Android App Development with Flutter, Rest Api integration with Frontend , PayMent getway like Stripe and razorpay implementation, GetX implementation.

EXPERTISE

- Proficient in JavaScript, React components, Redux, and other relevant technologies
- Improved the performance of a large-scale React application by optimizing data flow and implementing lazy loading.
- Created the Rest Api, microservices for React js web App and mapped with frontend.
- Proficient in Dart programming language, Flutter widgets, and other relevant technologies.
- Developed several mobile apps using Flutter, including an financial app.
- Implemented complex animations and transitions in Flutter apps, resulting in improved user engagement and retention.

PROFILE

Almost 2 Years of overall experience as a Software Engineer (Full-Stack Developer and Android Developer) in Arshaa Technologies (7 months) and 1.5+ years as freelancer. Worked in Hospitality business domain with expertise on Full Stack technologies and Andoid Developement. Also worked in HR Management, Project Management internal ReactJS Project for Arshaa Technologies and Wealthdekho, Pioneer Flutter Android App Project for Credmarg technologies and Tuffle Enterprises. Collaborated with backend engineering teams to build highly efficient and scalable Single Page Web Apps and Android Apps in Flutter with Agile Best Practices.

WORK EXPERIENCE

FullSatck Developer

Arshaa Technologies Pvt. Ltd.

03/2022-9/2022

 HR Management is a HR management Web App tool for an Software Company. We developed a React js Web App for the HR to help them with Holiday Management, Leave Management, OnBoarding Process and Projects management. Developed from scratch using Spring Boot and using Microservices .Used React material UI as a frontend and in Backend using Spring boot, MySql.

Project Title	Human Resources Management Internal (HRM)
Technology	Spring boot and MySql,Java Microservices
Role	Fullstack Developer
Description	Human Resources managers plan, coordinate, and direct the administrative functions of anorganization Developed from scratch using React Js And Spring Boot.
Duration	03/2022-9/2022
Responsibilities	 Worked as Full Stack Developer in this project. Created an Springboot server and connected MySQL to it. Implemented best practices of Spring boot and React JS to develop the application. Worked in Agile methodology and scrum framework for project execution

•

- Adhere to best practices in Flutter development, including widget reusability, state management, and performance optimization
- Integrated third-party APIs, such as Payment Gateway and Firebase, to add additional functionality to Flutter apps

LANGUAGES

English



Hindi

EDUCATION

B.TECH

Godavari Institute of Engineering and Technology, rajahmundary 2015-2021

Branch - Electronics and Communication Engineering

Intermediate of Science

Kartik oraon inter college,rantu

2013-2015

Matriculation

Rajiv gandhi high school, Burmu

2012-2013

CERTIFICATES

Software Engineer trainee Mearn Stact developer(pursueing from Prepbyte)

INTERESTS

Listening music

OTHER PROJECTS

Blog project in React,ToDo App in js and Feature Added and Bug Fixed in multiple Flutter Android Projects

WORK EXPERIENCE

Frontend Developer In Android App as freelancer

Credmarg technologies Pvt.Ltd

10/2022-03/2023

 We developed a Flutter Android App for the Gold Invester to help them to Gold buy, invest In gold , Buy Gold Items in EMI and sell Gold , Gold home delivery etc. Developed from scratch using Flutter and using Node js Microservice .Used Flutter material UI as a frontend and in Backend using Node Js ,Mongodb.

Project Title	WELTH DEKHO ANDROID FINANCIAL APP AND PIONEER SCHOOL ANDROID APP
Technology	Flutter and Node js Microservices, Mongodb
Role	Frontend Developer
Duration	10/2022-03/2023
Description	We developed a Flutter Android App for the Gold Invester to help them to Gold buy, invest In gold, Buy Gold Items in EMI and sell Gold, Gold home delivery etc from scratch using Flutter And Node js.
Responsibilities	 Worked as Frontend Developer in flutter. Creating Responsive layout to Adopt All android devices. Mapping Rest Api with frontend. Implimenting Payment getway. fixing bugs

Frontend Developer In Android App as freelancer

Toffle Entrerprises

7/2023-Till now

 We developed a Flutter Android App for School to help them to Manage Student Activity, To Notify Student on Notice and HomeWork etc from scratch using Flutter And Node js.

Project Title	PIONEER SCHOOL ANDROID APP
Technology	Flutter and Node js Microservices, Mongodb
Role	Frontend Developer
Duration	7/2023-Till now
Description	We developed a Flutter Android App for School to help them to Manage Student Activity, To Notify Student on Notice and HomeWork etc from scratch using Flutter And Node js.
Responsibilities	 Worked as Frontend Developer in flutter. Creating Responsive layout to Adopt All android devices. Mapping Rest Api with frontend. Implimenting Notification and Responsive layout and fixing bugs .